Aayush Kumar Full-Stack AI Engineer

≅ ak858098@gmail.com

Bengaluru, India

github.com/aayushkr99

9304154450

in linkedin.com/in/aayush-kumar-65993a235

♦ leetcode.com/u/aayushkr99/

Profile

As a Software Engineer, I develop, maintain and scale web applications using the **MERN** stack, **AWS**, **Docker** and **Kubernetes**, while integrating **AI technologies** for enhanced functionality. I leverage machine learning models to create intelligent features and personalized experiences. My core competencies include analytical thinking, creativity, teamwork, and communication across both traditional development and AI domains.

Professional Experience

2024 – present Bengaluru, India

Full Stack Engineer

Nexxio

- Contributed to a **SaaS** product for the MSME sector, handling **Backend**, **Frontend**, and **DevOps** to design and implement business-critical features.
- Set up a **Production** server using **Docker** and **AWS ECS** for a **microservices** application and configured **auto-scaling** as per requirements.
- Developed an **AI chatbot** using advanced AI technologies such as **RAG** (Retrieval-Augmented Generation), **Groq**, and **LangChain** to deliver contextual responses and enhance user interaction through **NLP-to-SQL** query techniques.

2022 – 2024 Bengaluru, India

Software Engineer

City Link Portal Pvt Ltd

• Worked on applications such as Store Quick, e-commerce, Planned Demand, and Tracking.

Projects

Candidate Engagement AI Chatbot 🛮

GitHub: https://github.com/aayushkr99/assignments-fullstack/tree/aayush-kumar-candidate-engagement-chatbot
Designed and developed an AI-powered candidate engagement chatbot using Node.js, and LLM APIs to deliver context-aware
job insights and extract candidate data conversationally. Implemented dynamic profile generation by parsing natural dialogue,
maintaining multi-turn context, and structuring insights without traditional form inputs.

MarkDown Editor 2

GITHUB: https://github.com/aayushkr99/markdown-editor.git

Developed a responsive web application that allows users to write and edit Markdown content with instant preview capabilities.

Skills

Backend / Frontend

• • • •

Cloud / Devops

 \bullet

Python, JavaScript, Node Js, Redis, Mysql, Mongo DB, TypeScript, React Js, DSA, System Design

Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, ECS, EKS, Azure, CI/CD, SQS, SNS, Route 53, S3, Cloud Front

ΑI

 \bullet

Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG), Embedding Models, ChatGPT, LangChain, VectorDB Agentic Al, Groq

Certificates

Backend Development Training (Designed, implemented, and developed backend applications such as Blogging Site, Book Management System, Social Media and Shopping Cart.)

Education

2017 – 2021 Punjab, India	Btech SVIET	GRADE : 86 %
2017 Ranchi, India	12th CBSE DAV Kapildev Public School	GRADE : 85 %